# Somdotta Sarkar

## **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer and open source enthusiast with a passion for writing clean code and creating accessible designs with **Ruby**, **Rails**, and **JavaScript** libraries. My background as an experienced teacher working in a highly intense and demanding environment equipped me with great communication skills, and ability to meet tight deadlines, and the strong work ethic needed to succeed in the tech world.

#### **TECH PROJECTS**

## **Somarven Arenas**

- -This is a website I built with two other peers that allow users to log in, see a list of arenas, register an arena or delete arenas, create reservations for arenas with city and date, and see the list of reservations.
- Built with: (ROR, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Bootstrap CSS3)

#### **Covid-data**

- This is a mobile web application I built to check a list of metrics (numeric values) that is created with React and Redux.
- one page with a list of items that could be filtered by some parameters;
- one page for the item details;
- Built with (React, Redux, CSS3)

## **Breaking Bad**

- I built this project based on an external API. Users can give likes and comments to the items.
- Built with (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MICROVERSE, Remote

## Professional Project Reviewer(Part-time), January, 2022- Continuing

- Selected by the Company among 100 other students for maintaining the performance throughout the course.
- Proposed improvements to the professional profile.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain the quality and showcase their strengths & abilities.

### Mentor (Volunteer), October 2021 - December 2021

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

iTutor Group, Remote

## Online English Consultant, March 2017 - November 2020

- All-Session Average Rating of 9.70 out of 10.
- Promoted to a Demo consultant, because of above-average student ratings thus helping the company grow.
- Promoted from junior to senior consultant after obtaining and maintaining a 9.5 student star rating.

Email
GitHub |LinkedIn |
Twitter | AngelList
Medium | Portfolio

#### **SKILLS**

**Front-end**: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-end: Ruby, Rails, SQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

**Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

#### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE, September,2021 – June 2022 Full Stack Web Development Program, Remote

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub,

National Institute of Electronics & Information Technology, July 2008 – June 2010 Post Graduation Diploma, Computer Application

- Online banking system
- B grade